You can't risk my mom's life over your mindset.
I don't understand what you're saying.
I just won't agree to it.
I'm her daughter.
I can take responsibility for my decision.
Can you?
I am her husband.
And I'm still your father.
The phone.
The surgery must be done.
What does she mean?
Dad.
What do you mean?
What "must be done"?
Not unless I'm the one in the hospital bed,
waiting for you to sign the papers.
What happened?
Why are you in such a rush?
My grandfather had a stroke back then.
The villagers got medicine for him,
but couldn't save him.
It was because his treatment was delayed.
Your mother just fell ill.
There's definitely still time.
Lingzhi is listed in here.
It's the guiding herb.
We can't do without it.
I grew up in the mountains.
I know how to find it.
Right.
I also have an old prescription here.
Try to get as many of the herbs as you can.
Even if you can't find them all, it's fine.
We finally convinced your father.
The surgery will be scheduled as soon as possible.
Don't worry.
What's this?
I found this in Lin Kanshan's
desk.
On the day he came to the mainland,
he brought this old newspaper from the airport.
It has dates and news,
and numbers in the articles.
I didn't know if it'd be useful,
so I copied them down for you.
Right, right, right.
I'm here, I'm here.
The new shop is being renovated.
Once it's done, I'll call you all back.
Don't worry, don't worry.
Goodbye, Sister Xia.
I'll miss you.
Sister Xia, I'll miss you so much.
It's fine.
With me around, would I ever shortchange you?
Here.
Thank you, Sister Xia.
Boss, Boss!
Sister Xia, Sister Xia!
I have elderly parents and kids to feed.
I can barely put food on the table!
Hold on, hold on.
Let's get in line first, alright?
Line up first, everyone.
Come on, guys!
If you don't line up, how can I pay you?
We've known each other for so long.
All these years.
Don't you trust what kind of person I am?
We trust you, of course we do.
The money is all right here.
Let's form a proper line.
I'll pay every single one of you today.
If you don't get paid, hold me accountable.
Everyone will get paid.
Everyone will get paid, don't worry.
You'll get it.
You will, that's a promise.
If you don't, come hold me to it.
All right, all right.
Thank you for understanding.
Thanks for understanding!
You're all here to collect your pay.
Right? I totally understand.
Sister Xia.
Look for that name.
When are you reopening?
Renovations are underway.
We'll reopen as soon as they're done.
I'm right here, don't worry.
Sister Xia.
Right.
Where's Boss Wen?
Boss Wen?
Next door, he's next door!
Yes, right over there.
Girl, let me go first.
I've got you covered.
Don't worry, come find me anytime.
Just come to me.
Didn't you go to Macau, China?
I called non-stop and you never picked up.
Afraid I'd cling to you?
I'm pregnant.
It's yours.
I'm pretty surprised.
That I've still got it in me.
I wanted to tell you ages ago,
but I couldn't reach you anywhere.
I had someone check.
It's a boy.
Why didn't you say so earlier?
Doesn't the smoke bother you?
No way, it's full of smoke in here.
Go inside, go inside, go on.
Let's stop testing for today.
Get some rest early.
Don't ruin your health,
or you'll have nothing left.
When we get old,
if one of us ends up in the hospital
waiting for surgery,
the other will need to make the call
and lend a hand.
You go to sleep first.
I'll try one last set.
Then wake me up early to take over.
What's wrong?
The front-page newspaper headline,
taking the initials of each first word,
plus the digits of his arrival date,
that's his base cipher.
We're stuck.
With so many passwords to guess,
it'll take us until 2026!
The base digits are already cracked.
Most of the passwords are the same.
You can't remember them, and neither can he.
So as long as the base digits stay the same,
we only have to guess the remaining digits.
Give one a try.
Attention.
Two of you are being released today.
Jin Chizhong, wait a moment.
Cao Liaoping, get ready first.
In five minutes,
someone will take you to the registration office.
Dismissed.
Congratulations, Brother Cao.
Cheers.
Congratulations on your fresh start.
Thank you.
It's been years since I had such a feast.
Went in back in '96,
got out in '09.
Thirteen years.
Thirteen years without seeing
this much delicious food.
What are your plans from now on?
Just take it one step at a time.
In 1995, you went to Beijing.
Using the money from Taiwan, China,
you bought an apartment in Chaoyang.
It was put under Cao Xiao'ou's name.
Do you know how much it's worth now?
It went up tenfold.
Can you believe that?
Of course.
It's now considered confiscated assets.
As for this key...
whether it ever returns to your hands
depends entirely on your performance.
Earning redemption through merit, to me,
has never been an empty slogan.
Remember that old classmate of yours?
Everyone's here!
Hey there, Old Zhang.
You're all here.
You're here so early, Mr. Zhao.
Little Cao got here even earlier.
What about Little Jia?
Why hasn't he arrived yet?
We're all here.
Is he outside smoking?
Which Little Jia?
Mr. Zhao's prized top rivals.
One ranked first in the school,
the other ranked second.
Speak of Cao Cao, and here he comes.
Jia Chunlin!
Mr. Zhao was just talking about you.
Engineer Jia.
Sorry, my apologies.
Don't shoot, don't shoot!
Take photos of the older folks.
Long time no see!
Old Cao!
When did you get out?
You got released
and didn't even let me know?
I should've thrown a welcome dinner
and treated you to drinks!
Are you serious?
Your favorite red wine...
It's stored at my place right now.
I bought it long ago,
kept it stored all this time,
until it's properly aged.
These past ten-odd years went by so fast.
Tell you what, you pick the place,
and I'll pick the time.
The two of us have to drink that wine.
No day like today.
Why not make it today?
Today really won't work.
After this wraps up,
I have another meeting.
Another day, another day.
Absolutely.
Jia Chunlin.
You make sure to remind me.
Mr. Zhao, please don't get up!
Students shouldn't make teachers stand.
Have you been here long?
Back then, you punished me by making me copy homework,
and I ended up the top Gaokao scorer!
You were smart.
It was all thanks to your own hard work.
Come on, everyone squeeze in closer!
Move closer together.
Switch spots, switch spots.
You stepped on my shoe.
Sorry, I'm so sorry.
So clumsy.
Didn't see it, my bad.
Little Cao.
Still as annoying as ever.
Pretty expensive shoes, huh?
Italian pigskin, handmade.
How much did they cost?
That stuff of yours...
How much will Taiwan, China pay for it?
Let's team up—make more and spend less.
Gotten brave, haven't you?
You want to go back to prison?
Aren't you afraid I'll report you?
Something you went through hell to get
should be sold at a high price.
One copy isn't enough.
If I were you, I'd sell two.
Everything is digital nowadays.
No more film rolls.
What are you storing it on?
A USB drive or email?
Everyone, say it with me!
Cheese!
For people from our parts,
starting with a cup of tea is the rule.
I'm happy. Truly thrilled today.
Liaoping is finally out.
See? Feels familiar, right?
Classmates for three years in high school.
As our homeroom teacher said, it's fate.
Today is our 40th high school reunion.
Liaoping...
How many 40-year spans do we get in life?
Look at the bond between us.
Same high school,
same college,
and the same workplace.
You survived a major ordeal,
and I'm here to throw you a welcome dinner,
truly happy for you,
so happy for you.
Come on.
If this isn't fate, what is?
To fate.
Remember that year we went to Beijing?
We both drank way too much.
I thought to myself back then,
you, Cao Liaoping—
as if I didn't know you.
You little bourgeois,
you only liked drinking red wine.
Who would've thought?
You'd chug Erguotou so ruthlessly too.
Aren't you tired?
What?
I asked, aren't you tired?
Like at school parties back then,
you did stand-up comedy on stage,
and not a single classmate laughed.
Don't you feel exhausted?
I just lacked the artistic talent.
Today, you're finally out.
I'm happy. Truly thrilled.
The last time we were here,
you asked if I had ever done
anything to betray our country.
Let's not bring that up.
I said I could swear an oath,
but the truth is, I lied.
For all my bluster,
I was terrified on the inside.
Just like you are right now.
Food this good...
Dig in.
When I was inside, I told them
that once I was out, I'd eat lobster every day,
until I threw up.
Until just the sight of it made me sick.
But you know what?
You never get sick of the good stuff.
Eat.
What do you want?
Society is a university.
And its current president
is named Ma Qi.
You and I...
could still be classmates.
Brilliant.
Forget "classmates."
From now on, you two are my bosses.
I'll do whatever you say.
Here's to a great partnership.
Clean this place up tomorrow.
Once Old Cao gets back,
you'll be working here from now on.
You can't smoke in here.
What are you laughing at?
Brother Qi,
a toast to you.
Since ancient times,
both at home and abroad,
intelligence work has always been about people.
With people, info flows from all sides.
Your funding has to go to someone anyway.
We just want to earn it.
I wouldn't dare lie to you.
Of all lines of work, this is the only thing I can do.
And deep down, I genuinely love it.
Back then, I just wanted to do the work.
Now, all I care about is making money.
My health hasn't been good these past two years.
I have to plan for my old age.
Brother Qi.
I believe that when it comes to
collecting and analyzing intelligence,
I have a certain talent and instinct.
I don't need much insider info.
Just by relying on
open news on TV and in newspapers,
and with a little study,
I can grasp a lot of hidden information.
The key to intelligence work
is spotting details and patterns in the news.
It's like picking a lock—once the key fits,
every door opens wide.
Humble as I am,
I just enjoy reading the news and papers,
analyzing every little detail.
Political trends and stock market trends
operate on the exact same logic.
No matter how many smokescreens are deployed,
there is always an underlying logic.
As long as you put yourself
in the shoes of the target,
and see things from their perspective,
even if a matter seems settled,
I can still deduce
the root causes of the outcome and its trajectory.
And once deduced,
every single piece is top-secret intelligence.
Brother Qi, if I'm not mistaken,
you're casting a wide net across the Taiwan Strait, right?
I'm willing to be one of your meshes.
And the more meshes you have,
the better it is, isn't it?
According to you,
you're best at predictive analysis.
There are many elections going on out there lately.
Tell me,
which winners can you predict?
The European Parliament elections,
Taiwan, China's "three-in-one" elections,
the Afghan presidential or Japanese prime minister elections...
Take your pick.
Since it's right next door,
let's bet on Taiwan, China.
Recently,
Taiwan, China's magistrate, mayoral,
councilor, and township mayoral races—
the "three-in-one" elections were held.
This is the Kuomintang's
first crucial electoral battle
since returning to power last year.
In the highly watched magistrate and mayoral race,
per Taiwan, China's election authority,
the winners include:
Chang Tong-rong of Keelung City,
Lin Tsung-hsien of Yilan County...
You really do know your stuff.
Cho Po-yuan of Changhua County,
Lee Chao-ching of Nantou County,
Su Chih-fen of Yunlin County,
Tsao Chi-hung of Pingtung County,
Huang Chien-ting of Taitung County,
Fu Kun-chi of Hualien County,
Wang Chien-fa of Penghu County,
Li Wo-shih of Kinmen County,
and Yang Sui-sheng of Lienchiang County.
How are things with Wen Zongshu lately?
His bathhouse business hasn't picked up,
but he's been busy with the intel business.
Still, it's all right under our noses,
and fully under our control.
Institute 761, Institute 762,
Xie Fengshi's workplace,
and the locations that recently surfaced...
I think it's all part of Zhu Yingjia's game.
His goal is to string these beads together
into a necklace.
Fortunately, we responded quickly.
Apart from the few beads
Cao Liaoping managed to steal earlier,
nothing else went as Zhu Yingjia wished.
If the day ever comes
when Ma Qi sides with them,
it'll be treason.
What are you getting at?
If he gathers intel just for the money,
why tip off Lin Kanshan?
Out of brotherly loyalty?
I think he's waiting
for the right opportunity
to use as a bargaining chip
to cut a deal with Zhu Yingjia.
He's far too ambitious.
I think he's completely out of control.
Do you think someone as smart as him
would defect to Taiwan, China?
The smarter a person is,
the higher their IQ,
the bigger the mistakes they make.
There was a lot I didn't believe before.
Now that I'm older, I'm not in control.
Lately, I keep having nightmares.
And feeling anxious.
I knelt over there for a bit just now,
and the panic went away immediately.
Isn't that amazing?
Did something happen?
Two of my friends passed away.
They didn't go in peace.
When we were young,
weren't we all wild and reckless?
Afraid of nothing under the sun.
As we get older,
there's much more to revere.
That's a good thing, too.
Brother Qi, all these years,
have you ever feared anything?
Of course.
Lately, I'm especially afraid of dying.
Lying in a hospital bed, barely living,
unable to live comfortably, yet unable to die.
I wonder what will become of us
when we grow old.
Yet I dare not get my fortune told.
It's like watching a TV drama:
you want to see the end, but dread it, too.
So you can only drift along in a daze.
Why are you so sentimental today?
Thinking of writing poetry lately?
Look at those who got caught.
It's always been the same, throughout history.
On the surface, it seems coincidental,
but in truth, it was all fated.
We think we're making our own decisions,
but Heaven already arranged it all.
When did Mr. Zhu's mother pass away?
You're quite well-informed.
Yesterday at one in the morning.
Pass along a message for me.
I want to go there myself.
To pay my respects in person.
Under the agreement between ARATS
and the Straits Exchange Foundation at their third summit,
the Cross-Strait Air Transport Agreement,
scheduled cross-strait maiden flights,
marking cross-strait air transport's
entry into regular operations.
Weekly round-trip flights
Over here! Over here!
will increase from the charter stage
of 108 flights to 270.
Since 2003,
cross-strait aviation went from charters to direct flights,
stops in Macau, China & Hong Kong, China
to just routing via Hong Kong, China's FIR
achieving historic breakthroughs time and again.
How many days, how many years I've waited...
waited until my eyes nearly went blind.
I was even afraid...
afraid I wouldn't see you before I retired.
You've lost weight.
At least six to ten jin.
My blood sugar is too high now.
If I don't watch what I eat,
they'll have to saw my leg off.
If I'd known this day would come,
back on that flight to Beijing,
I wouldn't have feared your stare.
Excuse me, could I borrow your newspaper?
Here.
Thanks.
There were none left when I tried to grab one.
You're welcome.
You know what?
One more second under that look,
and I would've pissed my pants.
People say women have intuition,
but that was the first time I realized
men have it, too.
If not for today,
I wouldn't know if I'd bet right.
My condolences, Brother Zhu.
With you here, it's a celebratory funeral.
Let's go.
Brother Qi, come take a seat.
What a feast!
Come, sit.
People in Taiwan, China,
still keep the custom of passing away at home.
They believe dying at home makes life complete.
Some families...
...even pull critical elders off care to take them home.
The hospital cooperates and issues discharge papers.
Aren't people greedy?
They want a good life and a good death to be at peace.
You are blessed.
The old lady passed away of old age.
You and your wife didn't have to suffer.
My blessing was waiting until you came.
Across the strait, from top to bottom,
there are so many people in intelligence.
Talk all you want about courage and wits,
there are only two and a half people I truly admire.
One is Wu Shenglai,
and the other is you.
Old Wu has retired now,
so I won't get to see him.
But since you could come...
...my life hasn't been in vain.
I don't represent the bullshit MIB.
I'm only here for myself.
In all sincerity, a toast to you.
You're my senior.
By seniority and etiquette,
I should've visited you first.
To tell you the truth,
earning your respect
is worth more than any golden Buddha.
Truly.
Besides the two of us, who's the half person?
It's all a haze.
You only see a shadow, not the man.
Mainland state security planted a mole right beside me.
I want to know who he is, too.
Do you know?
We're all tangled up in each other.
Zhang Fengge, Li Fengge...
The name doesn't matter.
What matters is finding him.
You spent half your life looking and never found him.
It'll be even harder for me.
It's been such a grueling search.
Back then, we had internal bounties.
As long as it was anyone
from Minzhong State Security Bureau's core staff,
a single photo and an address
had a fixed price, paid on time.
Now the budget is drying up,
making it even harder.
Lin Kanshan is even more capable than Yang Shiwen.
As long as those two legs aren't broken,
your eyes and ears
won't go blind or deaf.
What's the rush?
The fact his legs aren't broken
is thanks to you showing mercy, Brother Qi.
You did far more than just aim an inch high.
If you hadn't left that yarn
outside Lin Kanshan's door,
he would've been crippled long ago.
Just returning a favor.
We Chinese believe in reciprocity.
I'm not a Pixiu, hoarding without giving back.
It was just a small token in return.
How great is that?
You've had him by the throat ever since.
Now he answers to you better than to me.
Intelligence work is about making friends.
Too bad the young folks today don't get that.
They think intel work is just a job,
just punching the clock.
Not a shred of human touch.
It's getting harder and harder to lead the team.
What can you do?
One minute you preach pragmatism,
the next you demand loyalty.
Of course they won't listen.
That's why now, we talk brotherhood to outsiders,
and enforce strict rules within.
Honestly, as long as it's valuable intel,
it doesn't matter how you swallow it down.
Even if it's a pile of shit, I'd eat it.
At least it's still warm.
I hate the American way the most.
Claiming to be so rigorous,
with such meticulous procedures...
In the end, results are all that matter.
Getting what you want is the only real skill.
A general in the field must sometimes defy orders.
Winners take all.
Hasn't it always been like that throughout history?
Cheers.
However...
there must be rules.
Those are for mediocre fools.
True talent doesn't give a damn about that crap.
All I can say is, Brother Qi,
if Old Zhu had been your leader back then,
he would've worshipped you on an altar.
Disciplinary action, demotion, recall, reassignment...
Total madness.
Intel work is like drinking.
If drinking with Zhang San isn't fun,
I'll just go drink with Li Si.
What I hate most in life is feeling suffocated.
Why do I feel like in recent years,
your hands have been tied a bit, too?
Times have changed.
The economic gap with Taiwan, China
used to make turning people very easy.
Now the mainland has reform and opening-up,
the economy is booming,
and getting anything done is just too hard.
That aged wine is making me bloated.
I'm gonna go take a leak.
Where's the restroom?
Over here.
Okay.
Go ahead.
Liu Shangju.
Everyone calls her Sister Xia.
She's Wen Zongshu's courier.
She just finished the polygraph test next door.
Everything was stable at first,
but before halfway through, abnormalities showed up.
She never had any issues before.
This is the first time we caught something off.
How bad is the threat? Did you assess it?
What's your suggestion?
She knows everything
about Wen Zongshu and his background.
She was always reliable in the past.
Something must have happened recently.
In recent years, almost everyone got caught by the mainland.
And the couriers are always the first to slip up.
My suggestion is to detain her.
What good is detaining just her?
Didn't Wen Zongshu report anything?
No. He probably doesn't even know.
Got it.
You ruined Li Fengge.
You shouldn't have done that.
Why do I make money?
To fund her son's wedding and build a mansion.
Li Fengge's husband died because of me.
I promised him I'd look after his family.
Old Zhu, oh Old Zhu...
You completely wrecked my loyalty and honor.
Right, right. We shouldn't have.
The point is, you went after the wrong person.
A total waste of effort.
What could a mere peripheral player give you?
All these years, wasn't that enough trouble for you?
It's all dirt clods.
Put them all together,
and they're not worth the brick you brought.
This is a gold brick, after all.
A stepping stone. Courtesy demands reciprocity.
Can't let your little gold Buddha protect me for nothing.
What's in here?
761, 762.
Cao Liaoping, Jia Chunlin.
The pawns you've pushed for so many years,
every gain and territory is right inside.
I still want to take the rook and strike.
I want a steady stream of intel in the future.
That's easily served up.
As long as your appetite is big enough, brother.
Frankly, I'll sell intelligence to the whole world.
Not just to you.
I don't care who you flirt with.
Even if the same intel is split and rewoven,
as long as it's done cleverly enough,
making money from different countries
proves you're brilliant.
Money is important,
but satisfaction matters more.
This stuff is addictive.
Can't quit it.
In time,
I might sway the cross-strait intelligence tides.
Leak some intelligence today,
and tomorrow mainland operations get moved up.
Want to bet?
A lifetime of drinking, but today feels the best.
A toast...
to the king of underground intel in the Taiwan Strait.
To taking the rook.
I'm Wang Kai,
inviting you to watch the drama series
*Confrontation*.
You must recount your trip back to Taipei
to me in complete detail.
Not a single detail can be missed.
I'm not afraid.
Are you afraid?
When state leaders inspect a province,
who scouts ahead
and how they prepare in advance—
I really know nothing about any of that.
I wouldn't even know how to fabricate the details.
How can we determine which is the codebook?
Check which books
are starkly out of character for Lin Kanshan.
Why are you back?
Coming to my own home,
do I need to ask for your permission?